## Daniel Haggerty

(PHD, MCFE, OSCP)

Houston, TX, USA. 832-279-5505

I have an investigative and questioning mindset. I am hard-working, have a tenacious character and am a continuous learner. I changed careers from cutting-edge neuroscientific research to cyber investigations to find new and different challenges.

## EXPERIENCE

[2018 - Present] - Senior Consultant Cyber Investigations

### PNG Cyber, LLC (ProNet Group, Inc). Sugar Land, TX

- Conduct data forensic investigations for enterprise computer security incidents: ransomware, attacks/intrusions, business-email compromises, cloud-based forensics and intellectual property theft.
- Preservation and collection of digital evidence, knowledge of policies and procedures regarding chain of custody. Development of custom scripts to parse, classify and display digital evidence.
- Develop fact-based technical reports detailing events over specified periods of time.
- Flexibility to adjust to multiple demands, shifting priorities, ambiguity, and rapid change.
- Maintain clear and efficient communications with management and clients.
- Provide interactive discussion and guidance to peers.
- Discuss technical subject matter for a variety of audiences.

[2009 - 2017] — Post-Doctoral Research Associate

### Baylor College of Medicine Houston, TX.

- Extensive investigation of the neuronal networks underlying the relationship between memory and consciousness.
- Acquisition, analysis, and interpretation of complex neurophysiological data using MATLAB and Python.
- Mathematical understanding of probability, statistics, data-scientific methods, correlation, regression, Bayesian Inference, image classification and their analysis using computer programs.
- Presented work at international conferences and a history of publications in top-tier scientific journals.

## **SKILLS**

#### **DIGITAL FORENSICS INCIDENT RESPONSE**

- Knowledge of the full cyber investigation process from evidence acquisition to report writing.
- A deep understanding of Windows, Mac, and Linux operating systems and their respective forensic artifacts.
- Experience in on-site and remote acquisition of forensic artifacts and images: *Cybereason, Velociraptor, CyLR, FTKImager, Magnet Acquire, KAPE.*
- Deep knowledge of a multitude of tools used to carry out forensic analysis: *Magnet Axiom* (Certified), *EnCase, Splunk* and *Elasticsearch*.
- Developing *ad hoc Python* scripts/programs to perform a variety of forensic and artifact parsing functions.
- Office 365 Business Email Compromise investigations with customized PowerShell, Python scripts, IP geolocation (MaxMind API), Microsoft Admin console, Message Trace, Search Content and persistent inbox rules.
- Data Mining PII and PHI within various file formats (pst, E01, archives) with *Canopy*.
- Mobile phone forensic analysis and Cell Phone Data Record analysis (incoming/outgoing connections to cell phone towers) with *Oxygen Forensics*.
- Endpoint Detection and Response (*Cybereason*, *SentinelOne*)
- Block-chain analytics with *Elliptic*.
- Providing continuous and professional conversations and reports to keep clients, legal counsel, and insurance carriers updated regarding the status of the investigation process.
- Experience performing due diligence reviews of cyber insurance claims: Liaise with Insured, Carriers, and Vendors regarding invoices submitted to insurance carriers.

- Certified penetration tester (OSCP). *Kali Linux, Metasploit, BurpSuite, nmap*, password attacks, directory traversal, cross-site scripting, SQL injection, *PowerShell Empire*, privilege escalation techniques.
- A vast experience in understanding and communicating complex technical material in verbal and written reports spanning two disciplines (cyber investigations and neuroscience).

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING/DEVOPS**

I am an experienced software engineer primarily with the *Python, PowerShell, Bash, JavaScript, node.js, C#*, git versioning, *Docker* and cloud platform hosting solutions, *AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform.* I have developed a large number of scripts and programs built to solve interesting problems particularly related to ingesting, parsing, filtering and presenting data.

#### Forensics applications/scripting:

- Developed custom *Python* scripts for uploading *Microsoft O365* audit logs to ElasticSearch and enhancing the IP address data during upload with *Maxmind API* ip-geolocation and further IP information. Developed further *Python* scripts that can be used for subsequent downloading of significant results from *ElasticSearch* in *Microsoft Excel* formatted files (*Python* Libraries: *Elasticsearch*, *OpenpyxI*).
- Developed a *Python* program that ingests cell phone data records from *csv* files (*Verizon, ATT*, etc) and produces, for each phone call made/received, a map of the cell phone tower location and the sector/face of the cell-phone tower that communicated the call with the Azimuth (direction) of the cell tower sector (*Google Maps* API).
- Developed a *Python* script to take in any .csv file with an IP Address column and query the *Maxmind API* and return the input csv data enriched with columns of the equivalent IP lookup from *MaxMind API* data. The geolocations and accuracy radii of these data are also saved to a mapping html file for viewing IP geolocations in a browser.
- Developed a *Python* script to search and return all files of a certain extension (e.g., .evtx, .csv etc...) from nested subdirectories (for example from a *CyLR* triage collection) and copy them all to another directory, labeled with their origin/parent folder name. These collections can then all be pushed into other forensics tools such as *Event Log Explorer*.

#### **Non-forensics applications:**

- Development of a web application that returns a formatted *Microsoft Word* document with boilerplate text and a host of case-specific information (Insured/Client/Company addresses, names, people, dates). The data is pulled from two data sources (MSSQL database, PostgreSQL database) embedded as a starter template for report writing into *Microsoft Word* (*Python* Libraries: *Flask*), *Docker*, deployed as a *Web App* via *Azure Container Registry*.
- Development of a web application to query data from an MSSQL database and a directory of nested directories full of Microsoft Excel files and extract specific company data regarding engineers hours, travel time, expenses and display and export the data to formatted Microsoft Excel reports (Python Libraries: Dash, a heavy use of Pandas, Openpyxl, Google Maps API).
- Windows Forms C#/.NET desktop application for assembling, viewing, annotating photographs and exporting to a Microsoft Word document.

## PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

### Magnet Certified Forensic Examiner (MCFE) [SEPTEMBER 2020]

Completed following Magnet Courses [All 32 hours]:

- AX100 Forensic Fundamentals
- AX200 Axiom Examinations
- AX250 Axiom Advanced Computer Forensics
- AX300 Axiom Advanced Mobile Forensics
- AX310 Axiom Incident Response
- AX320 Axiom Internet & Cloud Investigations
- AX350 macOS Examinations

### Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP) [JULY 2019]

• The OSCP teaches ethical hacking methodologies: use of the tools included with the *Kali Linux* distribution to successfully attack and penetrate various live machines in a safe lab environment

## **Web-Development**

Digital-Crafts, Houston, TX. [16 WEEKS IMMERSIVE]

• Full-stack web-development program based upon Python, JavaScript, node.js, HTML, CSS.

## ACADEMIC EDUCATION

[2005 - 2009] - Doctoral Research

PhD Neuroscience Newcastle University, United Kingdom

[2002 - 2005]

**BSc Neuroscience** Leeds University, United Kingdom

[1997 - 2000]

BSc Sport Science Leeds Beckett University, United Kingdom

# **Publications**

Domenico C, <u>Haggerty DC</u>, Mou X, Ji D. (2021) LSD degrades hippocampal spatial representations and suppresses hippocampal-visual cortical interactions. Sep 14; 36(11) 109714. DOI: <u>10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109714</u>

Wu CT, <u>Haggerty DC</u>, Kemere C, Ji D. (2017) Hippocampal awake replay in fear memory retrieval. *Nature Neuroscience* Apr 20(4):571-580. DOI: <u>10.1038/nn.4507</u>

<u>Haggerty DC</u>, Ji D. (2015) Activities of visual cortical and hippocampal neurons co-fluctuate in freely moving rats during spatial navigation. *eLife* Sep 8; 4: 2015; DOI: <u>10.7554/eLife.08902</u>

<u>Haggerty DC</u>, Ji D. Coordinated sequence replays between the visual cortex and hippocampus. In: Analysis and Modeling of Coordinated Multi-neuronal Activity. (Editor: Masami Tatsuno). Springer, 2015.

**Haggerty DC**, Ji D. (2014) Initiation of sleep-dependent cortical-hippocampal correlations at wakefulness-sleep transition. *Journal of Neurophysiology*, Oct 1; 112(7):1763-74. DOI: 10.1152/jn.00783.2013

<u>Haggerty DC</u>, Glykos V, Adams NE, LeBeau FE. (2013) Bidirectional modulation of hippocampal gamma (20-80Hz) frequency activity in vitro via alpha( $\alpha$ )- and beta( $\beta$ )-adrenergic receptors (AR). *Neuroscience*. Dec 3; 253:142-54. DOI: 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.08.028